[
    {
        "id":1,
        "question":" Which of these best describes an array?",
        "o1":" A data structure that shows a hierarchical behavior",
        "o2":"Container of objects of similar types",
        "o3":"Arrays are immutable once initialised",
        "o4":"Array is not a data structure",
        "correct":"Container of objects of similar types",
        "level":1

    },
    {
        "id":2,
        "question":"How do you initialize an array in C",
        "o1":"int arr[3] = (1,2,3);",
        "o2":" int arr(3) = {1,2,3}",
        "o3":"int arr[3] = {1,2,3};",
        "o4":"int arr(3) = (1,2,3);",
        "correct":"int arr[3] = {1,2,3}",
        "level":1
    },
    {
        "id":3,
        "question":"What is an Array in C language.?",
        "o1":"A group of elements of same data type",
        "o2":"An array contains more than one element",
        "o3":"Array elements are stored in memory in continuous or contiguous locations.",
        "o4":"All the above.",
        "correct":"All the above.",
        "level":1
    },
    {
        "id":4,
        "question":"What are the Types of Arrays?",
        "o1":"int, float, char, double",
        "o2":"struct, enum",
        "o3":"long",
        "o4":"option 4",
        "correct":"All the above",
        "level":1
    },
    {
        "id":5,
        "question":"What is the maximun number of dimensions an array in C may have?",
        "o1":"1",
        "o2":"9",
        "o3":"16",
        "o4":"Theoratically no limit. The only practical limits are memory size and compilers",
        "correct":"Theoratically no limit. The only practical limits are memory size and compilers",
        "level":1
    },
    {
        "id":6,
        "question":"float marks[3] = {90.5, 92.5, 96.5}; int a=0; while(a<3) { printf(.2f,, marks[a]); a++;",
        "o1":"90.5 92.5 96.5",
        "o2":"90.50 92.50 96.50",
        "o3":" 0.00 0.00 0.00",
        "o4":"Compiler error",
        "correct":"90.50 92.50 96.50",
        "level":2
    },
    {
        "id":7,
        "question":"int a[3] = {20,30,40}; a[0]++; int i=0; while(i<3) { printf(%d, i[a]); i++; }",
        "o1":"20 30 40",
        "o2":"41 30 20",
        "o3":"21 30 40",
        "o4":"None of the above",
        "correct":"21 30 40",
        "level":2
    },

    {
        "id":8,
        "question":"what will be the size of myarray  </br> typdef char x[10]  xmyArray[5];",
        "o1":"15",
        "o2":"10",
        "o3":"50",
        "o4":"10",
        "correct":"50",
        "level":2
    },
    
    {
        "id":9,
        "question":"Which one of the following is the size of int arr[9] assuming that int is of 4 bytes?",
        "o1":"9",
        "o2":"36",
        "o3":"35",
        "o4":"None of the above",
        "correct":"36",
        "level":2
    }
    ,
    {
        "id":10,
        "question":"In C, if you pass an array as an argument to a function, what actually gets passed?"   ,
        "o1":"Value of elements in array",
        "o2":"First element of the array",
        "o3":"Base address of the array",
        "o4":"Address of the last element of array",
        "correct":"Base address of the array",
        "level":2
    },
    {
        "id":11,
        "question":"What is the output of C Program with arrays and pointers.? int main() { int a[3] = {20,30,40}; int (*p)[3]; p=&a; printf(%d, (*p)[0]); }"   ,
        "o1":"20",
        "o2":"0",
        "o3":"address of element 20",
        "o4":"Error",
        "correct":"20",
        "level":3
    },
    {
        "id":12,
        "question":"What is the output of C program with arrays and pointers.? int main() { int a[3] = {20,30,40}; int *p[3]; p=&a; printf(%d, *p[0]); }"   ,
        "o1":"20",
        "o2":"address of element 20",
        "o3":"Garbage value",
        "o4":"Error",
        "correct":"Error",
        "level":3
    },
    {
        "id":13,
        "question":"What is the output of C program with arrays and pointers.? int main() { int a[3] = {20,30,40}; printf(%d, *(a+1)); }"   ,
        "o1":"20",
        "o2":"30",
        "o3":"40",
        "o4":"60",
        "correct":"30",
        "level":3
    },
    {
        "id":14,
        "question":"void change(int[]); int main() { int a[3] = {20,30,40}; change(a); printf(%d %d, *a, a[0]); } void change(int a[]) { a[0] = 10; }"   ,
        "o1":"20 20",
        "o2":"10 20",
        "o3":"10 10",
        "o4":"20 30",
        "correct":"10 10",
        "level":3
    },
    {
        "id":15,
        "question":"What does the following declaration mean? </br>int (*ptr)[10];"   ,
        "o1":"ptr is array of pointers to 10 integers",
        "o2":"ptr is a pointer to an array of 10 integers",
        "o3":"ptr is an array of 10 integers",
        "o4":"ptr is an pointer to array",
        "correct":"ptr is a pointer to an array of 10 integers",
        "level":3
    }




     
]